<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Elasticsearch on Alexander Marquardt</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/elasticsearch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Elasticsearch on Alexander Marquardt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.153.4</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/elasticsearch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automating the Import and Export of Kibana Saved Objects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/elastic/automating-the-import-and-export-of-kibana-saved-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/elastic/automating-the-import-and-export-of-kibana-saved-objects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/kibana/current/introduction.html&#34;&gt;Kibana&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source data visualization and exploration tool used for log and time-series analytics, application monitoring, and operational intelligence use cases. It offers powerful and easy-to-use features that allow users to visualize data from Elasticsearch in various formats such as charts, tables, and maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Kibana offers a robust user interface for managing many tasks, certain operations can become tedious and time-consuming when done manually, especially for operations teams managing large and complex environments. One such operation is the migration of Kibana spaces and objects between environments—a task that can be critical in scenarios where clients cannot utilize the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/current/snapshot-restore.html&#34;&gt;snapshot/restore functionality&lt;/a&gt; provided by Elasticsearch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re-directing Elasticsearch documents with out-of-range timestamps that (would) fail to get written into Time Series Data Streams</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/elastic/re-directing-elasticsearch-documents-with-out-of-range-timestamps-that-would-fail-to-get-written-into-time-series-data-streams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/elastic/re-directing-elasticsearch-documents-with-out-of-range-timestamps-that-would-fail-to-get-written-into-time-series-data-streams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elasticsearch &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/current/tsds.html&#34;&gt;Time Series Data Streams (TSDS)&lt;/a&gt; are designed to provide an efficient and scalable way to handle time-based data within the Elasticsearch ecosystem. This feature is specifically optimized for storing, searching, and managing time-series data such as metrics, and events, where data is continuously indexed in chronological order. However, if events arrive with timestamps that fall outside of a pre-defined range, they will be lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog I will demonstrate logic that can be added to an Elasticsearch ingest pipeline which can be used to intercept documents that would be rejected by the TSDS index due to timestamp range issues, and to instead redirect them to a &amp;ldquo;failed&amp;rdquo; index. The documents that are redirected to the &amp;ldquo;failed&amp;rdquo; index may (for example) be used to raise alerts and examined.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combining Elasticsearch stemmers and synonyms to improve search relevance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/elastic/combining-elasticsearch-stemmers-and-synonyms-to-improve-search-relevance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/elastic/combining-elasticsearch-stemmers-and-synonyms-to-improve-search-relevance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is now published on Elastic&amp;rsquo;s official blog. Please check it out at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elastic.co/blog/improve-search-relevance-by-combining-elasticsearch-stemmers-and-synonyms&#34;&gt;https://www.elastic.co/blog/improve-search-relevance-by-combining-elasticsearch-stemmers-and-synonyms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
